Guide to the Northwestern Live Stock Company Records 1884-1961
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Northwestern Live Stock Company Records
1884-1961
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 031
Northwestern Live Stock Company
3 reels microfilm
The Northwestern Live Stock Company was established to acquire, raise, and sell sheep, cattle, horses and other livestock in Choteau County, Montana. The collection contains the organization's financial and legal records.
Location of originals unknown.
Historical Note
The Northwestern Live Stock Company was incorporated in Helena, Montana, in 1901 by John T. Murphy, A.L. Smith, J.P. Woolman, and John B. Turton to operate in Shonkin, Choteau County, Montana. The company was organized to acquire, raise, and sell sheep, cattle, horses, and other livestock. The president of the company until 1906 was John Murphy, who then disposed of his interest. In 1909, J.H. Evers entered the company and by 1951 was president of the company.
The collection contains the financial and legal records of the Northwestern Live Stock Company. There are a complete set of corporate minutes from 1901 to 1941, that document board of director's meetings, stock issuance, capitalization, and reorganizations. Interspersed with other financial records are immunization records, herd counts, and livestock sales. Many of the legal records concern land leases, purchases, transfers, and negotiation of grazing permits with the U.S. Forest Service. The earliest land records appear in abstracts of title attached to later documents.
The materials are arranged by folder or volume, with no series divisions.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and the University of Montana--Missoula.
Loaned for microfilming by Jon Evers. He retained the originals.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
United States. Forest Service
Shonkin (Mont.)
Animal industry--Montana --Chouteau County; Livestock--Montana -- Chouteau County
Business records -- Montana--Chouteau County
Montana; Agriculture; Labor History
- Cash book, 1934-1949; 1 (Reel 1)
- Ledger, 1941-1961; 2 (Reel 1)
- Minute book, 1937-1941; 3 (Reel 1)
- Ledger, 1934-1941; 4 (Reel 1)
- Ledger, 1931-1941; 5 (Reel 1)
- Minute book, 1901-1941; 6 (Reel 1)
- Financial records, 1911-1938; 7 (Reel 1)
- Leases and other land records, 1884-1919; 8 (Reel 2)
- Cancelled checks, 1921-1923; 9 (Reel 2)
- Stock certificates, 1901-1938; 10 (Reel 2)
- Ledger, 1933-1941; 11 (Reel 2)
- Day book, 1912-1913; 12 (Reel 2)
- Day book, 1907-1916; 13 (Reel 3)
- Wage slips, 1921-1922; 14 (Reel 3)